xprize.org 2018-09-03

# XPRIZE Privacy Policy | XPRIZE

**Effective Date: September 10, 2014**

XPRIZE.ORG (“Site”) is a website of the XPRIZE Foundation, Inc. (“XPRIZE” or “we” or “us”), an educational nonprofit corporation established for the purpose of creating and administering competitions designed to inspire breakthroughs for the benefit of humanity and for the purpose of getting elementary and secondary students excited about S.T.E.A.M. education (Science, Technology, Engineering, Arts and Math).

 **USE OF THIS SITE OR PROVISION OF ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO OUR TERMS OF USE AND OUR PRIVACY POLICY. DO NOT USE THIS SITE IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO OUR TERMS OF USE AND OUR PRIVACY POLICY.**

Our privacy policy explains how we collect personally identifying information about you, what information we collect, and how we use such information.

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) is incorporated into and is subject to the XPRIZE foundation **Terms of Use** **** for XPRIZE.ORG (“ **Terms of Use**”), an agreement between you and the foundation regulating your use of this Site.

Please note that terms used, but not defined, in this Policy are defined in the **Terms of Use**. Please see the **Terms of Use** for more information on your use of this Site.

 **In this Policy:**

  *  **How Do You Agree to this Policy?**
  *  **Changes and Updates to this Policy**
  *  **What Information Do We Collect through this site?**
  *  **Why Do We Collect and Use Your Information?**
  *  **How Do We Collect Your Information?**
  *  **Use and Protection of Your Information**
  *  **How Can You View Your Information We Have Collected?**
  *  **How Can You Update Your Information?**
  *  **Children’s Personal Information**
  *  **Our Information Sharing Policy**
  *  **International Access**
  *  **Sharing As Required By, or Permitted By Law**
  *  **Sharing In Order to Protect Rights, Property, and Safety, and to Report Unlawful Activity**
  *  **Sharing In Cases of Sales, Mergers, or Acquisition**
  *  **Your Comments**
  *  **Third Party Websites and Payment Processors**
  *  **Donation Processing**
  *  **Who to Contact With Questions?**

 **How Do You Agree to this Policy?**

You agree to this Policy by visiting/and or using this Site. If you cannot agree with this Policy, then please refrain from visiting/and or using this Site.

 **Changes And Updates to this Policy**

We reserve the right to change, add, subtract, update or amend all or any part of this Policy at any time without notice to you. We will post any updated Policy on this Site and each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of this page by its effective date. By visiting and /or using this Site after the changes to this policy, you are deemed to have agreed to the said new terms or changes to the policy.

 **What Information Do We Collect through this Site?**

  *  **Personal Information**  
We collect information that can be used to identify you personally (“personal information”), such as your name, mailing address, company name, telephone number, and email address. We do not collect any personal information about you unless you provide it voluntarily, including, without limitation: (i) by filling out a form or survey; (ii) by posting a Comment (as defined in the **Terms of Use**); (iii) by requesting promotional material; (iv) by registering an account and e-mail address with us; (v) by signing up for an e-mail newsletter; or (vi) by e-mailing us. If you do not want us to collect personal information about you, you can simply decide not to submit it to us or use this Site

  *  **Other Information**  
The Site does have an analytics system installed provided by third party providers and we store anonymous user interactions with our analytics system.

 **Why Do We Collect and Use Your Information?**

We collect information that is used to optimize the user experience of our visitors.

We collect your information: (i) to send you newsletters and other information about XPRIZE activities and events; (ii) to keep you informed about future events and competitions; (iii) for Site administration; (iv) to improve or optimize our services and future competitions; and (v) for the purpose of performing any other services for which such data was collected. We also collect donation information so that we can reach out to donors for our XPRIZE loop program. You may contact us using the form below if you decide at any time to stop receiving mailings.

We may also use your personal information to:

  * Respond to your inquiries;
  * Contact you about changes to our policies;
  * If you apply for a job, we will use the information you provide to find out about you and provide to service providers or others we deem relevant to the job application;
  * Performing statistical, demographic and market analysis of the users of this Site;
  * Processing your employment application; and/or
  * Comply with and/or conform to requirements of the law or to comply with legal process served on us.

 **How Do We Collect Your Information?**

We collect information to provide you with a better use of this Site and related activity.

We collect your personal information through:

  * The information you provide to us;
  * Using an analytics system; and
  * The information we get from your use of this Site and this information will include but is not limited to your device information, details of how you used this Site and your internet protocol address.

  *  **Personal Information**  
We collect the personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when you use this Site. For example, if you request information about our competitions or submit a Comment, as defined in the **Terms of Use**, we will collect any information that you provide to us in such request or submission.

  *  **Other Information**  
Like the operators of most websites, we may use tracking software and similar technology, which automatically collects information about your computer hardware and software, and use of the website. This information may be used by us for the operation of the website and to provide general statistics regarding use of the website.

  *  **Web Tracking Method**  
We may collect information regarding your visit to this Site using cookies and other web tracking methods. A cookie is a small amount of data that is created by a website and saved by your web browser or equipment and its purpose is to remember information about your visit to this Site and your preferences.

 Cookies allow website operators to better customize visits to the website to the visitor’s individual preferences. Many commercial websites use cookies. We may use cookies on this Site to allow us to, among other things, measure activity, to personalize your experience, and to track your status or progress when requesting products, services, or information. If you choose, you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can manually delete individual or all of the cookies on your computer by following your browser’s help file directions.

However, if your browser is set to reject cookies or you manually delete cookies, you may have some trouble accessing and using some of the pages and features that are currently on this Site, or that we may put on this Site in the future.

  *  **Response to “Do Not Track” Indicators**  
Our analytics system will not track users who use the do not track option on their browsers.

 **Use and Protection of Your Information**

As noted in the **Terms of Use**, you granted us a license to use your Comments, and we may use those Comments (not in conjunction with your personal information) for marketing, promotional, and any other commercial or non-commercial purposes.

We may also decide to use information about you to track how you use this Site. In addition, we may aggregate the personal information that you provide with the personal information that other users provide in order to conduct research, analysis, or studies for our own purposes (i.e., not related to providing you with specific services).

Whenever we obtain your personal information, we will use reasonable practices to protect your personal information from unauthorized access or disclosure. While we will use such efforts, we cannot and will not act as insurers of the security of your personal information. We assume no liability for any disclosure of data due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third party access or other acts of third parties, or acts or omissions beyond our reasonable control.[  
](https://d/Users/zachary.david/Desktop/XPRIZE%20Privacy%20Policy%209.9.14.docx#_msocom_1) ****

 **How Can You View Your Information We Have Collected?**

Users cannot currently view information we have collected about them.

 **How Can You Update Your Information?**

Users can update their email address in our newsletter system at any time. If at some point, we ask users to sign up for XPRIZE.ORG, we will allow them to update their personal email and information on XPRIZE.ORG.

 **Children’s Personal Information**

Do not provide any personal information unless you are at least 13 years of age.

We do not want, and this Site is not designed to solicit, information from children under 13 years old. If a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information, a parent or guardian may so inform us by clicking on the contact page below. We will use and make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database, subject to applicable law and policy.

 **Our Information Sharing Policy**

Except to provide our services to you or to provide information to you as described above and except for the situations below, we do not rent, sell, or share your information with other people or companies.

 **International Access**

This Site is operated in the United States. By using this Site you consent to have your personal information transferred, processed and stored in the United States. Your personal information will be subject to the terms set out in this Policy and subject to the **Terms of Use**.

 **Sharing As Required By, or Permitted By Law**

We may share your personally identifiable information as required by, or permitted by law. This may include sharing your personally identifiable information with governmental entities, or third parties in response to subpoenas, court orders, other legal process, or as we believe is necessary to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims that have been brought against us, or to defend against possible legal claims that we determine in our sole discretion might be brought against us.

 **Sharing In Order to Protect Rights, Property, and Safety, and to Report Unlawful Activity**

We may also share your personally identifiable information if we determine, in our sole judgment, that the release of your information may protect the rights, property, or safety of you or another person. In this instance we may share your information with law enforcement or any other person or entity we determine, in our sole judgment, may be able to protect you or the other person. We may also report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful, or that we reasonably believe may aid a law enforcement investigation into unlawful activity.

 **Sharing In Cases of Sales, Mergers, or Acquisition**

Where XPRIZE becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, personal information may be provided to the entities and advisors involved subject to a confidentiality agreement, and we will provide notice before any personal information is finally transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

 **Your Comments**

If you post a Comment to this Site, you acknowledge that the information that you choose to post, including any personal information that you choose to post, may be available generally to the public. You also acknowledge and represent that such Comment is not confidential or proprietary to you or any other person or entity. See the **Terms of Use** ****  for more details on Comments.

 **Third Party Websites and Payment Processors**

This Site and/or our e-mails may link to third parties’ websites. It is also possible that third parties’ websites or e-mails may link to our Site. Such third-party websites may have privacy policies that are substantially different than this Policy. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third parties. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of these websites before transmitting any personal information to third parties.

We process your payments through third-party payment processors and do not maintain any records of your credit card or debit card information submitted through this Site.

 **Donation Processing**

Donations are processed through third-party providers. They store all the personally identifiable information on their servers since they are PCI compliant. All the transactions appear to be secure and are independent of the XPRIZE servers.

 **Who do you Contact with Questions?**

You may contact us using the form at **http://xprize.org/contact** with any questions, complaints, or claims.
